# YOONJOO LEE

## voonjoo.lee@kaist.ac.kr | voonjoolee.com

#### RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interest lies in the intersection of human-computer interaction (HCI), natural language processing (NLP), and Education. I aim to support people to learn from and understand information-dense text (e.g., lecture transcript, scientific article) by structuring the information in the context to create conversational questions and answers to scaffold people's understanding.

#### **EDUCATION**

KAIST Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science. Advisor: Juho Kim Sep. 2020 – Present

Ewha Womans University

M.S. in Statistics (Applicational Statistics). Advisor: Dongwan Shin B.S. Major in Mathematics Education, Minor in Statistics Graduated with Honors (*Magna Cum Laude*)

University of California, Davis

Davis, CA, USA

Exchange student in Mathematics

## **PUBLICATIONS**

## **Conference and Journal Papers**

[C6] CogQA: Answering Advanced Questions on Scientific Articles (TBD)

**Yoonjoo Lee**\*, Kyungjae Lee\*, Sunghyun Park, Dasol Hwang, Jaehyeon Kim, Hong-in Lee, Moontae Lee *Accepted in ICML 2023* 

[C5] DAPIE: Interactive Step-by-Step Explanatory Dialogues to Answer Children's Why and How Questions

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Sundong Kim, Yohan Yun, Juho Kim

CHI 2023: Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

[C4] Promptiverse: Scalable Generation of Scaffolding Prompts Through Human-AI Hybrid Knowledge Graph Annotation

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Tae Soo Kim, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim

CHI 2022: Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems

[C3] Personalizing Ambience and Illusionary Presence: How People Use "Study with Me" Videos to Create Effective Studying Environments

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Jean Y. Song, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

CHI 2021: Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

[C2] A Machine Learning Approach that meets Axiomatic Properties in Probabilistic Analysis of LTE Spectral Efficiency

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

ICTC, Oct. 2019

Last Updated: May 3, 2023

Seoul, Republic of Korea

Mar. 2018 - Feb. 2020

Mar. 2014 – Feb. 2018

Sep. 2015 – Feb. 2016

#### [C1] Probabilistic Analysis of Spectral Efficiency for LTE based on PDCCH Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Yeonkyu Park, Seungken Park

IEEE Communications Letters, vol. 23, no. 9, Sep. 2019

## **Posters and Workshop Papers**

# [P5] LMCanvas: Object-Oriented Interaction to Personalize Large Language Model-Powered Writing Environments

Tae Soo Kim, Arghya Sarkar, Yoonjoo Lee, Minsuk Chang, and Juho Kim

CHI 2023 Workshop on Generative AI and HCI

## [P4] Interactive Children's Story Rewriting Through Parent-Children Interaction

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

ACL 2022 Workshop on Intelligent and Interactive Writing Assistant

## [P3] XDesign: Integrating Interface Design into Explainable AI Education

Hyungyu Shin, Nabila Sindi, Yoonjoo Lee, Jaeryoung Ka, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim

SIGCSE TS 2022 Posters

### [P2] A Study on the Distribution Analysis of LTE Resource Block Usage from TSME Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

# [P1] A Study on the Estimation of Probability Distribution of the Spectral Efficiency of LTE based on TSME Measurement Data

Yunbae Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### Allen Institute for AI (AI2)

Seattle, US

Research Scientist Intern, Semantic Scholar Team (Mentor: Pao Siangliulue, Joseph Chee Chang, Jonathan Bragg)

May 2023 -

## LG AI Research Seoul, Republic of Korea

Research Scientist Intern, Advanced Machine Learning Lab (Mentor: Moontae Lee, Kyungjae Lee)

Nov. 2022 - March. 2023

- Designed a schema for questions triggered from academic papers by adapting prior literature in education to a paper reading context.
- Collected various advanced questions based on the proposed schema from academic paper readers [C6].

#### KIXLAB, KAIST Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Graduate Research Intern (Mentor: Juho Kim, Jean Y. Song)

Mar. 2020 – Aug. 2020

• Investigated user experiences with VR services by analyzing large-scale text data using various techniques like clustering, topic modeling, and sentiment analysis.

## **Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI)**

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Graduate Research Assistant, Data Sciences Group (Mentor: Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park)

Mar. 2018 - Dec. 2019

- Performed analysis of Spectral Efficiency for LTE with probabilistic modeling and Deep Neural Networks. [P1, C1, C2]
- Participated in research about predicting future Resource Block Usage by applying stochastic modeling and Recurrent Neural Networks. [P2]

Undergraduate Research Intern, Data Sciences Group

Jan. 2018 - Feb. 2018

• Devised a module for pre-processing and summarizing mobile traffic data in Python.

Last Updated: May 3, 2023

### **TEACHING**

Introduction to Social Computing
KAIST CS473, Instructor: Juho Kim

Time Series Analysis
Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Dongwan Shin

Regression Analysis Fall 2018

Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Donghwan Lee

## **SERVICES**

### **Program Committee**

• CHI LBW 2023

#### Reviewer

- CHI 2023, 2022
- UIST 2022
- ACL 2023
- CSCW 2023
- C&C 2022
- IEEE Transactions on Learning Technologies

#### **Student Volunteer**

CHI 2022

KAIST-Google ExploreCSR
Student Organizer

Programming Mentoring
Leader of Student Organizer

2022
2016 – 2017

Mathematics Mentoring in Ewha Girls High School

Mentor

2015 – 2017

## HONORS, AWARDS, AND SCHOLARSHIPS

Research Assistant Scholarship

College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University

Admission Scholarship 2018

College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University

Honors Scholarship 2014, 2015, 2016, 2017

College of Education, Ewha Womans University

**Dean's List** 2014, 2015, 2016, 2017

College of Education, Ewha Womans University

Ewha Womans University Alumnae Association Scholarship 2017

College of Education, Ewha Womans University

Last Updated: May 3, 2023

Spring 2019